<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

  <!--     Entrance letter text     -->

  <!--Letter Title-->
  <BDC_LetterTitle>You arrive at the distress signal.</BDC_LetterTitle>
  <!--Anomaly-->
  <BDC_Chimera>Squeals and roars of abominations sound like war horns, as chimeric monstrosities snort and tear at the defenders before you, their unbalanced adrenal glands and hormones driving them toward the murder of anything even vaguely humanoid shaped. An intended design by the mad machine god, or merely a happy accident? Either way, they are between you and your deserved reward.\n</BDC_Chimera>
  <BDC_Fleshbeast>The shriek of twisted abominations pierce the sky, as shambling mounds of tendon and bone slouch toward the defenders. As you notice the mounds of flesh that have overgrown the small settlement’s walls, there is a foul, sickly sweet smell, not unlike rotting meat, that makes you gag. Flesh sacks tremble as they digest their victims, supplying nutrients to the surrounding fleshmass.\n</BDC_Fleshbeast>
  <BDC_ShamblerNoPall>The smell hits you before you even reach the settlement, and then you see the shambling hordes that have already swarmed the defenders. The acrid taste of deadlife dust infuses the air, a death pall storm that clears above you now. The doors of homes and dining halls lay broken as undead have swarmed the town, but now there is hope to put them down for good, to be buried deep.\n</BDC_ShamblerNoPall>
  <BDC_ShamblerPall>The smell hits you before you even reach the settlement, and then you see the shambling hordes that have already swarmed the defenders. The acrid taste of deadlife dust infuses the air, a death pall storm that looms above you. The doors of homes and dining halls lay broken as undead have swarmed the town, rising nearly as soon as they fall. You’ll have to deal with all these bodies.\n</BDC_ShamblerPall>
  <BDC_Horax>Hateful chants fill the air of the settlement, cultists arranged in profane rituals as ghouls assault the defenders without mercy or humanity. Symbology of Horax is painted over the walls of the bunkhouses and dining halls, and you briefly wonder if the cult managed to infiltrate beforehand. Either way, any traitors have made their loyalty clear at this point, which’ll make the job easy.\n</BDC_Horax>
  <BDC_Sightstealer>Even without seeing them, the blood chilling scream of the sightstealers reveals their presence. You see them, emaciated phantoms that stalk the village streets, flashing in and out of the visible light spectrum as bioferrite talons slash into their victims. It is another terrible hunt of these creatures that has called the alarm, closing in only when it is too late for their victims to defend.\n</BDC_Sightstealer>
  <!--Stages + Tech Level-->

  <BDC_NeolithicStage1>Arrows whistle overhead as spearheads are jabbed into abominations; the warriors of the tribe rallying against the demons sent by the Dark God. Brave warriors find themselves surrounded yet fight onward, their will yet to be broken. Most of the tribe has fled, but those that remain fight on with the discipline of space marines. They are ready to die, yet perhaps you can even the odds.\n</BDC_NeolithicStage1>
  <BDC_NeolithicStage2>Arrows whistle overhead as spearheads are jabbed into abominations; the warriors of the tribe are stuck in against the demons sent by the Dark God. Brave warriors have found themselves surrounded after buying time for their tribe to escape, yet they fight on with unbroken spirit. The wounded clutch at their bleeding guts; it is a desperate scene, but you could make a difference.\n</BDC_NeolithicStage2>
  <BDC_NeolithicStage3>Arrows whistle overhead as spearheads are tiredly jabbed into abominations; the warriors of the tribe hold a ragged defense against the demons sent by the Dark God. The bravest warriors lay dead in mud churned by the siege, as surviving tribesmen defend the wounded that pray while clutching pale wounds. The usual fate of tribes that defy Horax, yet there is hope in your arrival.\n</BDC_NeolithicStage3>
  <BDC_NeolithicStage4>The bloodied mud is littered with broken arrows and spear shafts, as the warriors of the tribe have been overwhelmed by the machinations of the Dark God. Their bravery bought time for the tribe to make distance and escape, and now they have paid the price for their attempt at heroism. As the abominations shamble through the shattered camp, you spot a few dying survivors still.\n</BDC_NeolithicStage4>
  <BDC_NeolithicStage5>Miasma chokes the remains of the tribal campsite, shattered bodies of its defenders litter its soil with bow and spear still clutched tightly in hand. You see the body of a priest draped over the broken remains of a comms console; to the tribe it must have been a holy artifact. To the priest, they must’ve known somehow that it could save the tribe. A shame that salvation came too late.\n</BDC_NeolithicStage5>

  <BDC_MedievalStage1>Battle horns sound as sword and shield clash against abominations; noblemen and their levies contest to gain the most glory against the foul enemy as their heraldry waves proudly in the fight. The men-at-arms attempt to form a proper defense, but it's clear they are unused to fighting such an enemy. The blue blood officers seem to be holding the line, but are still vastly outnumbered.\n</BDC_MedievalStage1>
  <BDC_MedievalStage2>Battle standards wave tattered from the battlefield of the campgrounds of the garrison, as nobles attempt to rally their levymen into a proper defense against the abominations of the Dark God. Yet the militia is clearly tired, already a vast number of the peasants drag themselves screaming through the mud. They might still win the day, but cold logic shows how the fight will likely end.\n</BDC_MedievalStage2>
  <BDC_MedievalStage3>Two days of pitched combat against the abominations of the Dark God have taken their dire toll. Conscripted peasants have found themselves surrounded on all sides now, and fatigue leaves them barely able to raise swords and shields to defend their wounded against the tide of death. As the officers attempt to rally, men-at-arms raise shields once more, but are clearly exhausted.\n</BDC_MedievalStage3>
  <BDC_MedievalStage4>Three days of siege against the local garrison have borne fruit, as the defenders lay broken and dying in the mud, their blood painting the victory of the Dark God better than any tapestry. Heraldry of proud families lay forgotten in trodden battle standards, torn from the banners on their walls as monsters devour what remains of a peasantry’s heroic last stand. Yet, some still live.\n</BDC_MedievalStage4>
  <BDC_MedievalStage5>Maggots make their feast as flies buzz through the campsite, bodies of noble and peasant alike torn down with their heraldry and their proud walls, as abominations shamble through the ruins. A scholar’s body is draped over a shattered comms console. Perhaps they thought it was a device of divinity, or they knew the truth about the distress signal. Either way, they’d hoped to be saved.\n</BDC_MedievalStage5>

  <BDC_IndustrialStage1>Bullets fly through the camp as the defenders attempt to rally against the abominations; it seems the outpost was caught unawares, thinking this small settlement was safe for being off the map. While most of the settlement has been evacuated, those that remain exchange uneasy glances as the bravest colonists bark orders. It seems the fragile discipline of the militia is soon to break.\n</BDC_IndustrialStage1>
  <BDC_IndustrialStage2>Bullets fly through the camp as the defenders are stuck in against the abominations, caught unawares but still holding the line, with the wounded trying to hold their own wounds closed. It looks like most of the outpost has been evacuated, and those that remain were trying to buy time for the others to escape. The town militia has been holding the line, but they won’t last long now.\n</BDC_IndustrialStage2>
  <BDC_IndustrialStage3>Bullets fly through the camp as the abominations have carved their way through the defenders; two days they’ve held the line, buying time for the civilians to make distance and escape. Now it is a desperate struggle to survive, as the militia’s discipline has been broken. Some still fight, and others are ready to flee as soon as they see you’ve arrived. While the wounded cry out to be saved, the bravest of them lay dead in the mud, ground underfoot by the creations of Horax.\n</BDC_IndustrialStage3>
  <BDC_IndustrialStage4>Moans echo through the camp as abominations have overwhelmed the defenders; in three days of heavy combat the camp’s militia had done their best, but their best was not enough. Nothing remains of the colonists but heroes bleeding out in the mud, crawling as far as their fragile bodies will take them. Most of them lay dead, clutching their weapons, mouths agape in silent screams.\n</BDC_IndustrialStage4>
  <BDC_IndustrialStage5>The settlement’s walls are pockmarked with the scars of bullets and painted in dried blood. You see a body draped over the broken remains of a comms console, hand still tight on their sidearm. Miasma chokes the streets of the camp; nothing remains of the defense but their legend, and the family they gave precious time to escape. Perhaps it was enough time for them to find sanctuary.\n</BDC_IndustrialStage5>


  <BDC_SpacerStage1>Sounds of pulse charges and screaming abominations ring loud, as plasteel armor and combat implants do their best against the playthings of a mad Archeotech God. The soldiers hold their own against the monsters, they have the discipline and equipment to make the attackers bleed for every inch. But the horde is seemingly without end, and their escape route is cut off entirely.\n</BDC_SpacerStage1>
  <BDC_SpacerStage2>You hear the strained shouts of officers and the bark of pulse rifles contest against the chorus of screaming abominations as you near the campground. Power armor and painstoppers can only do so much against the machinations of a mad Archeotech God. The soldiers have given time for civilians to escape, but now they are trapped. Without intervention, this will be their last stand.\n</BDC_SpacerStage2>
  <BDC_SpacerStage3>Two days of pitched combat against the abominations of a mad Archeotech God, and the gunfire of the camp’s soldiers is scattered, overwhelmed by the occasional terrified shout as another defender is felled by the foul playthings of Horax. Top of the line equipment and martial discipline have taken the soldiers of this outpost far, but without intervention, they’re soon to join the dead.\n</BDC_SpacerStage3>
  <BDC_SpacerStage4>Three days of abominable assault have borne fruit, as the shambling horrors of Horax lurch through the smoking ruins of the outpost. Perhaps they were treasure hunters, or scientists trying to find some way to close off the reach of the mad Archeotech God. Some survivors still bleed in the mud, hoping to go unnoticed amongst the dead. Perhaps they can give you some answers.\n</BDC_SpacerStage4>
  <BDC_SpacerStage5>The streets of this little town are choked with its dead, as the abominations of a mad Archeotech God shamble through the shattered defenses of its garrison, rotting away in the battlefield’s mud. You see a garrison recruit slumped over the shattered remains of a comms console, they must have been the one who sent the distress signal. Judging by the dead, they at least put up a fight.\n</BDC_SpacerStage5>

  <BDC_UltraStage1>Lasers fire from disciplined battlelines, the combat zone smells of fresh ozone while abominable limbs tear at hyperweave uniforms, as soldiers fight onward. These are the best of the best; many civilians have evacuated by this point, and the garrison fights with discipline and duty to buy time for non-combatants to flee the battlefield. But even Glitterworld soldiers fall under enough strain.\n</BDC_UltraStage1>
  <BDC_UltraStage2>Officers rally their soldiers as the abominations break through the defensive line, containing their panic in the face of near death. Plasma and pulse charge meet sinew and bone, as the garrison holds the line against the siege still. Yet even Glitterworld tech falls to enough enemies. They’ve bought time for all the civilians to flee, but now the garrison themselves are in need of a rescue.\n</BDC_UltraStage2>
  <BDC_UltraStage3>Two days of combat stuck in against abominations have yielded grim results, as scattered laser fire sounds off from the surviving garrison of the outpost. Glitterworld soldiers lay choking in their own blood despite all their proud uniforms and pulse rifles, as the survivors attempt to rally a proper evacuation. Yet they are surrounded; without intervention, the defenders will surely die.\n</BDC_UltraStage3>
  <BDC_UltraStage4>Three days of defense against the abominations of Horax and the proud defenders have fallen, broken banners lay stained in mud and blood. Soldiers quietly hide amongst the bodies, hoping against hope that their distress signal will bring reinforcements before they bleed out. Horax has won this battle, and its triumph is clear in the broken dignity of the Glitterworld elite soldiery.\n</BDC_UltraStage4>
  <BDC_UltraStage5>Defenders lay shattered in the mud like so many broken toy soldiers, cast to the ground by an indifferent child as the abominations of Horax trudge through the battlefield. Miasma chokes the campground, for despite all their training and technology, pain and fatigue took their toll. The body of a Glitterworld cadet lay slumped over a broken comms console, face frozen in surprise.\n</BDC_UltraStage5>


  <BDC_ArchotechStage1>The Archeotechs do not battle each other directly, instead preferring to settle their disputes through servants and proxies, a tale as old as the first kings of humanity. In the settlement the forces of Horax battle against the acolytes to a rival AI god, the screams of abominations clash against the hum of vanometric energy cells, as the defenders hold the line with faith and steel.\n</BDC_ArchotechStage1>
  <BDC_ArchotechStage2>Battle wages between the Archeotechs ahead, as the abominations of Horax contend with the servants of another AI rival. Members of the outpost hold their own for now, but the defenders are slowly but surely losing ground to the horde they have battled for a whole day already. The injured look to the golden green glow around them, as if their God will surely intervene quickly.\n</BDC_ArchotechStage2>
  <BDC_ArchotechStage3>Two days of combat have waged between the Archeotech Gods now, as Horax sieges the camp of their rival to slaughter the mortal servants. The scene of abominations and human servants cutting into each other is reminiscent of a chess board before you, as if the AI deities move their creations and acolytes about like game pieces with no care or sorrow. Already, soldiers lay dead.\n</BDC_ArchotechStage3>
  <BDC_ArchotechStage4>Three days of siege have decided the game between Archeotech rivals, the AI Gods that have contested this little patch of land and the lives of their servants and creations like game pieces. Abominations shamble through the smoldering ruins as the defenders drag themselves through mud, delirious and dying, crying out to their deity to save them even as they readily bleed out.\n</BDC_ArchotechStage4>
  <BDC_ArchotechStage5>Vanometric power cells lay shattered as the abominations of Horax shamble through the ruins of the outpost, the Archeotech God having little care for the creations of its AI rivals. The pathways are choked with the dead, with even the technology of an ultimate intelligence, the defenders were nothing but tokens, gambled. Over a broken comms console, a dead acolyte lay sprawled.\n</BDC_ArchotechStage5>

  <!--Obelisks-->
  <BDC_Mutator>An awful twisted obelisk looms over the settlement, foul and powerful in presence, it dominates the landscape. Looking over the local defenders, you see mutations hidden under clothing; stray tentacles and bone whips twitching within sleeves, residents slowly seem to be turning into flesh beasts. You wonder if the dark marker is a totem of fearful dread, or reverence to this little village.\n</BDC_Mutator>
  <BDC_Abductor>Uncomfortable energy flows through you, nauseous lightning crackles from the warped obelisk these settlers have built their colony around. Friend and foe, human and abomination, all turn their heads towards the monument if for but a brief moment. Something is coming, and everyone can feel it. You get the notion that whatever your business is here, you should finish it quickly.\n</BDC_Abductor>
  <BDC_Duplicator>Putrid energy looms over the settlement, the smooth obelisk commanding the attention of all in the isolated village. You spot two defenders in close proximity, and at first glance they seem as if they might be twins - but they share not just the same face, but identical scars, each as faded as their compatriots own. Even their build is identical, as if a perfect copy. Is it linked to the obelisk?\n</BDC_Duplicator>


</LanguageData>